All right, as I record this video, Stylecraft is going to hand you two things. A 4.99% fixed
interest rate, which is the lowest financing rates in Bell County, or up to $20,000 in flex cash.
But not everybody likes Stylecraft. Today, we're going to get into the pros, the cons, the
incentives, the neighborhoods, and everything else that Stylecraft has to offer. All right, let's
get into it.
My name is Taylor Dasch with EG Realty. I do not work for Stylecraft. I always recommend getting an
actual real estate agent to take you through these new construction homes, so that way you have all
of the information and you make the best decision for you. All right, let's get into this video.
All right, so this one is probably the most common question that I get asked, is Stylecraft a good
builder?
So here's what I'll say. In this price range, they are one of the best builders. Now, you can get a
Stylecraft home anywhere from 220,000 and they have a new neighborhood that goes all the way around.
The neighborhood that goes all the way up to the high three to 400,000 point in the homestead.
Their homes are solid. I've had a lot of clients who have purchased properties with Stylecraft and
I always recommend that they get an inspection.
If they don't, I get the inspection for them and every single time the inspection has costed more
than any findings on the inspection.
Then on top of that, you're going to have a one-year door-to-door warranty.
They have a whole separate team for the warranty. What is it?
They have a whole separate team for making sure you're taken care of after closing.
A lot of the times you move in, you may find something wrong. You call them up and they're going to
take care of you.
Now, they have some complaints online. Every builder does.
You're not going to leave a review for like a new construction unless you're dissatisfied probably.
So, take that with a grain of salt. Take my advice with a grain of salt.
I always recommend getting the inspection anyway. But as far as if they are a good builder or not,
I would say they are and they're one of the better builders in this price range.
All right, so now the financing. So, first, let me take a side note here.
We're in the Homestead neighborhood. This is Stylecraft's newest neighborhood.
They really answered a large demand here in the Temple Belton area.
New construction, these homes are on half an acre at least.
They are built a little bit differently. Stylecraft always kind of, they build their homes
with kind of the theme of the neighborhood. Definitely something to check out.
They're already selling. So, if you want to get one, if you're looking for new construction,
and you want a little extra space, it's definitely something to look into.
Reach out to me. I'm going to get you set up with their latest incentives in this neighborhood
and the available inventory. Alright, so, the financing.
This is one thing that I think sets Stylecraft apart, just in general,
is that they offer 4.99% fixed financing for 30 years.
Or, if you want to use your own lender, you can get the $20,000 flex cash.
Now, these incentives change monthly. So, in August, they're going to August 2026.
They're going to have new incentives.
But, I've done deals almost every other month with Stylecraft, and their incentives are based off
of the supply and demand.
And they've been staying pretty steady recently. So, I would expect them to be right around there.
Now, what does that mean for you? So, at a 4.99% interest rate, on a $315,000 house you're looking
at,
about 1600 a month, whereas at the market interest rate, which is going to be all right here,
you get your market interest rate, you're looking at a $300 savings per month.
So why is that important? Because number one, over five years, that equates to about $20,000.
And number two, it gives you leverage on your exit strategy on the property.
You can resell the property, you can rent it out, you're going to have a lot more wiggle room with
a lower monthly payment.
Which is great, especially on the neighborhood in South Pointe where the entry price is right
around $220,000.
You're going to be able to live comfortably in that. You're going to be able to stack up some money
and kind of start building towards the next thing.
Now...
Alright, so you're saying, "Taylor, what's the catch here?" The catch is that if you, to get this
fixed interest rate, you have to go with Kangaroo Lending, which is like 49% owned by Stylecraft.
So they are, they are kind of building their own company with that. They are...
So you have to use their lender for these incentives. If you do not use a stylecraft lender from kangaroo
lending, you're gonna forfeit the interest rate. Now for the flex cash, you can still use that.
I don't like it whenever builders use their own in-house lending to lower the interest rate,
but I definitely see the business side of it. So listen, what do you do with this information?
Now you compare your lender, which I'm gonna get you set up and just as a side note,
three of the past five closings I've had with Stylecraft. Now, just as a side note,
about 75% of my clients have used about 75% of my clients that went with a stylecraft home
have used my lender. So be sure to weigh the extra fees, weigh the interest rate, the payment, the
savings overall
and then make your decision and I'm gonna help you out with all of that.
I'm gonna make sure you have all of the information before even writing the contract.
Alright, one more thing till we get to the next. One more thing and then we're gonna get to the
next section of this video.
Whenever I did my research on this video, there is another builder offering, very low incentives.
There's another builder offering.
There's another builder who price matched Stylecraft's incentive rate where we can compare them.
I'm going to get you set up with the best new construction for you.
But first, let's get on to what you're actually buying whenever you buy a Stylecraft home.
First, let's get into Stylecraft. They were founded in 1988 out of college stations, and from what
I have access to, they had 973 closings last year, and they're a top 75 builder in all of the
United States.
As far as the quality of the homes themselves, so they are engineered slab, which is a big one in
Texas.
You have James Hardy siding, you get granite countertops, and then smart home systems that come as
the standard package.
Now, here's the part that I'm not going to leave out. Listen, I have closed quite a few Stylecraft
homes.
We've done inspections on all of them, and I've never had one single large issue.
It's always been something cosmetic. Now, there are a few reports that show plumbing issues or
drainage issues.
That is something that you have to get checked out. That's why I always say get an inspection.
I'll pay for the inspection. Just make sure you get it done because you don't want something like
that to bite you in the future.
Now, with that, the other reason for the inspection is that you have proof showing that this house
was good.
So, whenever you have to get a warranty on something, you can say, "Look, here's the inspection.
This is how everything was and now where it's at." For their warranties, you have one year door-to-door.
So, what I tell people is, if something's really bothering you, give him a call to the warranty guy.
You're going to have his number. He's going to get you set up.
The one complaint I have had from one of my clients is that they do sometimes take a while to get
back to you.
They're always right back with me, and I told them, "Get with my client," and they got right with
my client.
So, props to them for that. At the very end of the one year door-to-door, give them a call.
Write down every single little, tiny, picky thing that you can think of and have them come fix it.
It's free. It's under warranty. If you don't get it during the first year, you're not going to get
it.
So, they have a two-year warranty on the system, so the plumbing, the HVAC, the electrical,
and then a 10-year structural warranty. That comes pretty standard with new builders here.
One other thing I will say about the quality is that every single one of these properties
has to get approved by the city. They have to pull permits.
It's all documented that the work was done correctly.
If you've had to deal with any permits, I will tell you, it is not an easy process.
They don't just say, "Oh, this looks okay. You're good."
Now, they come in and they inspect it, and they want to ding you on things
so that they can come out and re-inspect it.
And then for the inspection, another reason to get the inspection is that
if, for some reason, you decide to sell in, you know, three, five, seven, ten years,
that inspection is probably still going to be pretty accurate, which is useful for me.
As a realtor, I can upload the inspection that way you overcome a lot of buyer objections
just by having the inspection up.
All right, so I see a lot of people make this mistake, especially with new construction.
The price that you see on Zillow, the price that you see on realtor,
is not the actual price as far as the monthly payment goes.
The price is likely based off of the county assessment whenever there was no house on the property.
So you have to keep that in mind, and then what they are advertising is going to be principal and
interest payment.
They're not factoring taxes and insurance.
Which, by the way, with any new construction, your insurance payment is going to be lower,
so there's a few offering, like, $69 per month if you go with their in-house insurance.
But you're going to actually be cutting costs on that, and if you buy a new construction,
because you buy a resale home, especially an older one, the insurance is going to go up.
So like I always say, always check the percentage taxes, the NUD, the PID.
And in fact, what that is monthly based off of the price that they are listed at.
So a few cons here is that Stylecraft, they do pretty much like a gold date in their contracts.
So how the process works is you get under contract, we're going to do the negotiating.
I'm going to get you the best deal possible.
And then they're going to set a time for an initial walkthrough.
The initial walkthrough, one to two weeks before closing.
Now that is whenever you're going to go in, you've already got the third party inspection.
They already should be taking care of those things.
You're going to go in and you're going to put your blue tape on every little defect that you see.
And then the next week you're going to go in and say, "Hey, this looks good?" or "This doesn't look
good."
And then they're going to make sure they get every single item fixed and then you'll close.
One thing I will say for Stylecraft, I don't know what the deal is.
Every single appraisal that I've done with them has come back quite a bit higher, like $10,000 to $15,000
higher
than what we have in our contract for, and that's not including the rate buy downs.
The additions and the flex cash that you're going to be using in the transaction.
All right, so who is Stylecraft for and who is Stylecraft not for?
So I think Stylecraft is an amazing builder for someone who values that lower monthly payment,
who's okay with being an entry price point in a neighborhood that may be a little bit further out
from Central Temple, Belton, etc. If you're okay with, I don't even want to say lower quality
finishes
because the one thing I love about Stylecraft is the price is lower but they're still giving you
nice finishes
in my opinion. Now you're not going to be like Kiela level finishes, Corothers or something
obviously,
but for the price point I think that's why I rank them highly because you're getting decent
finishes.
You should not go with Stylecraft if you want to make customizations. They're not going to change
anything. Typically they've already ordered everything for the property. Maybe if you
get in super early on, but I have not had success with getting them to change something.
and then if you have pretty much like a low tolerance for having to wait for these people to get to
you after closing.
I only say that because I don't want to risk you guys going with a Stylecraft home and then what.
and then they don't get back with you just like what happened to my client until I say something or
your realtor says something.
so keep that in mind that's just my personal experience.
and then if you want to be like in a certain section of Temple there they are I feel like they're
they find these opportunities
and that to fill up vacancy on the market and then they take them which is another reason I really
like them but they're not in all of the most popular neighborhoods
in the Temple, Belton area.
(footsteps)
Now, with that being said, they are in 12 communities, they just pushed into Troy, 4 different
school districts,
and then pricing from 220 all the way up to the low 400s in this neighborhood homestead.
With the pricing from like the 220,000 pointe in South Pointe to all the way up to the low 400,000s
right where we're at now in the homestead.
All right, so tailors. All right. All right. So my take on Stylecraft, we're going to give them 3.9.
That is based off of the Temple, Belton, Area Builders. That's based off of the price. It's the
quality.
The customer service, the smoothness of the transaction, how they care for you after closing.
And then my general experience with them so far. So take that with a grain of salt. I do work with
them quite often.
[Music]
But the most important thing, like I always say, is do not go into a Stylecraft model home by
yourself.
You want to have somebody there who is objectively, who is viewing your situation, who is a
professional, and who is working for what is best for you.
And then you also, what brings you leverage is going to be the inventory, the options that you have
available.
So if you go into a model home, you speak with a builder, they can already probably tell in your
eyes that you like it.
And you haven't seen all the other builders, you probably think you're going to get a good deal.
But then whenever you buy the property and then you're down the line, you realize you're in really
big trouble with the equity in this thing.
Or whatever the case is, it's always best because they're not going to say, "Yeah, this one's overpriced."
But I will tell you that, I will make sure that you are getting the best deal for you.
That is the full Stylecraft breakdown. There is a super detailed page on my website, TempleTexasHomes.net/Stylecraft.
It's going to be right down below. If you are buying new construction in Temple, if you're relocating
to Temple, please reach out to me.
I'm working with people just like you every single day. I would love to have a private conversation.
I'd love to have a private conversation with you and see if we will be a good fit working together.
I hope you all enjoyed this video. Let's get it.
Look, I'm going to try. This may not go in the video because it's a comparison.
I was told to not do any more comparisons. We'll see. I don't know.
So how does Stylecraft compare? I think Stylecraft, in my opinion, is going to be a step up kind of
above the D.R. Horton
and the Linner, new construction, but then kind of a step down right below Omega.
And they're pricing reflects that. And they're pricing actually reflects that and then some.
They're actually going to give you a better deal. I think based off of just value alone, they're a
very good builder.
A very good option here in Temple.
The one thing is you're not going to, it's not common to see like quartz countertops.
Whereas, you know, Omega or Kiela, they'll throw some quartz countertops in from time to time.
The flooring, I personally really like Stylecraft's flooring, but you know, objectively.
I mean, Corothers and Kiela, they have nicer finishes. Their homes are also quite a bit cheaper.
So, I think value definitely is there in a Stylecraft home.
The super premium finishes, they're not going to be like you would be in like Corothers or Kiela.
And then customer service, I think, I like them a lot of the times like linear, especially.
The transactions are not smooth, they're not coordinated well.
There's just a lot of things that I can see on my end that also spills over into the customer
service on your end.
I know if you go with a Stylecraft home, worst case scenario, I'm going to reach out to them and
say,
"Hey, they bought a house with you guys, get them set up, and they're going to get you set up."
Alright. Alright, so now for the review.
One last little quick bit on Stylecraft that it, for me, it means a lot because I put a high value
in putting the client first.
Their customer service has been great. I've asked them to come do a video on a day that they're off
and they will send somebody up there.
I've never not been able to see a Stylecraft home. They respond fast. Their transactions are very
well laid out.
They typically will have a builder rep in every single model. The builder reps know what they're
talking about with the Stylecraft homes.
So I personally like that. I think that's a huge sign that they are training people right, that
they're doing right, and that they're training people right.
And that they're training people right, and that they have a system that they know.
If they put the client, the customer first, it's going to pay them back in the long run, which is a...
Which is something that I think is 100% true. All right.